Well.
글쎄요
Hello there.
안녕하세요
Look, I know what you're thinking.
무슨 생각하는지 알아요
You're thinking I peaked too early.
내가 너무 일찍 정점을 찍었다고 생각하죠?
Last week was an amazing climax.
지난주 클라이맥스는 굉장했어요
We built a model that massively outperformed the frontier.
우리는 개척지를 훨씬 능가하는 모델을 만들었어요
It can't get better than that.
Get it, get it, get it, it, it, it, it! 이보다 더 좋을 순 없죠
Well, I've got news for you.
한 가지 알려드리죠
It's going to get better than that.
Get it, get it, get it. 더 좋아질 거예요
We are actually going to have the best week yet.
최고의 한 주가 될 거예요
And it's just getting started.
이제 시작이에요
So this week, this week it's about reaching the pinnacle.
이번 주에는 정점에 오를 거예요
It's about becoming a master of LM engineering.
LM 공학의 달인이 되는 거죠
And we're going to do it.
그렇게 할 거예요
We're going to have a blast.
정말 재미있을 거예요
It's going to be epic.
에픽이 될 거예요
Uh, we are going to build a multi-agent framework.
다중 에이전트 프레임워크를 구축할 거예요
We're going to build a solution that is going to be really, really awesome.
정말 정말 멋진 솔루션을 구축할 거예요
And yeah, it's going to do something profound and it's going to do it using everything that we've been
뭔가 심오한 일을 할 거예요 지난 8주간 지은 모든
building for the last eight weeks.
걸 활용해서요
Uh, for today, though, we're going to be using modal, the serverless platform for AI, so that we
오늘은 인공지능을 위한 서버 비 플랫폼인 모드알을 사용할 겁니다
can deploy the same model that we built last week, our proprietary Three specialized alum, we're going
지난주에 만든 것과 같은 모델인 독점적인 3단계 명산을 배포하기 위해서요
to be able to deploy it behind a serverless API on the cloud, and we're going to build the first agent
클라우드에서 서버리스 API 뒤에 배포할 수 있습니다 많은 에이전트의 첫 번째를 만들 거예요
The first of the seven agents that are going to be part of the solution that we are building this week
이번 주에 우리가 만들 복잡한 사업 문제를 해결하는 데 일조할
to solve a juicy business problem.
7명 중 첫 번째 요원이죠
So without further ado, let's get into week eight, the final week of mastering LLM engineering.
그럼 지체 없이 8주 차로 넘어가죠 LLM 엔지니어링의 진수를 보여주는 마지막 주예요
And of course, it wouldn't be the start of a week without this picture.
이 영화가 없으면 일주일의 시작도 아니죠
For the last time, let's look at the journey that you've been on.
마지막으로 여러분이 걸어온 길을 살펴보죠
You started or seven weeks ago, uh, you first uh, we we spent some time looking at frontier models,
7주 전에 시작했나요? 아니면 처음 시작했나요? 우리는 개척 모델에 대해 시간을 좀 들였습니다. 질문을 하고
uh, looking at asking questions, asking how many times that A appeared in this sentence, if you can
A가 이 문장에 몇 번이나 나왔는지 물어봤어요. 기억하실지 모르겠지만
remember that, uh, in week two, we built UIs.
2주 차에 UI를 구축했어요.
We experienced gradio for the first time.
처음으로 그러디오를 경험했어요
We worked with agent ization in a light way.
아이즈 요원과는 가볍게 작업했어요
It's going to get a lot heavier.
Get up! Get up! 훨씬 더 무거워질 거예요
Uh, and we played around with Multi-modality in week three, we went open source with hugging face
3주차에는 다중 양상을 다뤘는데요 얼굴을 껴안는 것과 토큰화
with tokenization, with with models.
모델로 오픈 소스를 했죠
In week four, we built that amazing code generation tool that rewrote Python a, C plus, plus.
4주 차에 놀라운 코드 생성 도구를 만들었습니다 파이썬 a, c, 플러스 플러스 코드를 다시 쓴 도구죠
And in doing so, we explored how you select the right LLM to solve a business problem.
그러면서 비즈니스 문제를 해결하기 위한 올바른 LLM을 선택하는 방법을 알아봤죠
In week five, we tackled Rag using Lang Chain and built a question answering project.
5주 차에는 랑 체인을 활용해 래그와 씨름했고 질문 답안 과제를 만들었죠
Maybe you built something bigger as well.
더 큰 걸 지었을지도 모르죠
In week six.
6주 차에요
Week six was when we started on training and we fine tuned a frontier model and week seven.
6주 차에는 훈련을 시작했고 개척지 모델을 조율했어요 7주 차에는
Of course, week seven we've just come from was when we beat that frontier model using Cultura fine
7주째에는 개척 시대 모델을 이겼어요 코튜라 미세 튜닝을 이용해
tuning to make our own Verticalized specialized LLM.
수직화된 전문 LLM을 만들었죠
And I loved it and I hope you did too.
정말 좋았어요 여러분도 좋아하셨길 바라요
And so this week, week eight, the culmination of everything that's come before is when we have a finale.
그래서 이번 주, 8주 차에는 그동안의 모든 것이 정점을 찍고 결승전이 펼쳐져요
We must LLM engineering and we're going to do it by focusing on Agentic AI and building an agent platform.
에이전트 인공지능과 에이전트 플랫폼 구축에 초점을 맞춰 LLM 엔지니어링을 진행할 거예요
Let's talk more about that next time.
그 얘기는 다음에 하죠